내 이름은
올리버 퀸
My name is Oliver Queen.
지옥 같은 섬에서
5년을 보낸 후
After five years
on a hellish island,
하나의 목표로
집에 돌아왔다
I have come home
with only one goal--
내 도시를
구하는 것
to save my city.
다시 살인자가
될 수는 없다
But to do so, I can't be
the killer I once was.
죽은 친구를
기리기 위해
To honor my friend's memory,
I must be someone else.
다른 사람이
되어야 한다
다른 무엇이
I must be something else.
애로우 지난 이야기
전 배리 앨런이에요
- Previously on "Arrow"...
- I'm Barry Allen,
센트럴 시티
경찰서에서 왔어요
from the Central City
police department.
전 CSI팀과
함께 일하죠
I'm with the crime scene
investigation unit.
도와줄 친구도 있죠
I have friends
that can help.
- 미라클이 죽일 수도 있어
- 어서 해
- This miracle could kill you.
- Do it.
그건 인간 병기를
만들어 낼 혈청이지
It was a serum designed
to create human weapons.
누가 제조법이라도
찾아냈다는 건가?
You think someone
found the recipe?
원심 분리기와
막대한 혈액으로
A centrifuge
and a large supply of blood.
누군가 대량으로
제조할 생각이야
I think someone wants
to make more of it.
- 올리버!
- 살아있나?
- Oliver!
- Is he alive?
- 펠리시티, 우린 못 살려!
- 그래요. 우린 못하죠
- Felicity, we can't save him!
- You're right. We can't.
Ow!
제발 내 친구를 구해줘
Please save my friend.
어서 잡아요!
Hold him!
살아남기 힘들거야
He's not going
to make it.
살아날 거에요. 체내에
남은 걸 찾아내야 해요
He will. We just have
to find out what's in his system.
제,제가 하는 건
죽은 사람이에요
I--I--I usually only
work on dead people.
배리!
Barry!
신체에 이런 반응을
불러 일으키는 건
All right, I can
think of four possible diagnosis
네 가지 정도로
떠올릴 수 있죠
for what's causing his body
to react this way.
이젠 세 가지...
Make that three
possible diagnosis.
둘
Two.
흉부 압박
시작해요
Start chest
compressions.
됐어요
Got it.
고통스러운 건 정맥
혈액의 응고 때문이에요
He's suffering from
intravenous coagulation.
이상하게 응고되고 있어요
마치 메이플 시럽처럼
His blood is unnaturally clotting.
It's like maple syrup.
제발 구해줘요,
알았죠?
You can save him, right?
쥐 문제가 있어
다행이에요
Lucky you guys
have a rat problem.
농담해?
죽을지도 몰라!
Are you kidding?
That'll kill him!
제가 안하면
회장님이 죽어요
He dies if I don't.
- 펠리시티...
- 해요!
- Felicity...
- Do it!
적절한 양을 투여하면
혈액을 희석해서
Just the right amount of this stuff
will thin his blood enough
다시 순환하게
만들 거에요
to get it
circulating again.
어서 가, 올리버
Let go, Oliver.
죽어가고 있어
He's crashing.
더 이상 싸우지 마
Don't fight anymore.
올리버, 깨어나요!
Oliver, stay with me!
나랑 같이 가
Stay with me.
♪ Arrow 2x09 ♪
Three Ghosts
Original Air Date on December 11, 2013
♪ Arrow 2x09 ♪
Three Ghosts
Original Air Date on December 11, 2013
Sync, corrected by elderman
www.addic7ed.com
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
한글자막 by 클라투
www.jinubeck.com
올리버, 놔 줘
올리버!
- Oliver, let him go.
- Oliver!
도대체...
What the...
도대체
무슨 일이지
What the hell
is going on?
강력한 혈액 응고제가
투여된 거죠
You were injected with
a strong-acting blood coagulant.
위험할 수도
있었다구요
You would have
stroked out, ahem,
운좋게도 꽤 효과적인
혈액 희석제를 맞았죠
but fortunately you had
a very effective blood thinner handy.
와파린이라고
Warfarin.
흔히들 쥐약이라고
알고 있죠
Better known as rat poison.
이 친구가 자넬
살렸네, 올리버
Kid saved your life,
Oliver.
지금은 위급 상황에서
생명을 구한 사람에게
This is the point
in a lifesaving emergency
감사해야 할
타이밍이에요
where you thank
the person that did the lifesaving.
- 내가 누군지 말했겠군
- 네, 그랬죠
- You told him who I am.
- Yeah, I did.
그건 자네가 밝힐
비밀이 아냐, 펠리시티
That's not your secret
to tell, Felicity.
그건 내가 결정해
I decide who finds out
my identity.
동의를 구할
시간이 없었어요
Well, we didn't
have time to get your vote,
의식을 잃고
죽어갔으니까요
what with you
unconscious and dying.
그가 여길 떠나서
경찰서로 갔다면?
What happens if he leaves here
and goes right to the police?
- 안 그랬을 거에요
- 전 안 그래요
- He wouldn't do that.
- I wouldn't do that.
- 그를 믿어봐요
- 그럴 수 없어!
- I trust him.
- I don't!
그래서 어쩔 셈이죠?
활이라도 겨누려구요?
What are you going to do,
put an arrow in him?
- 생각 중이야
- 걱정 말아요
- I am considering it.
- Don't worry,
농담이니까!
이게 뭐가 다르죠
he's kidding! How is
this any different
어머님이 회장님을 쏴서
제게 도움을 청했을 때랑?
from when your mother shot you
and you came to me for help?
어머님이 총을 쏘셨어요?
- Your mother shot you?
- Or when you brought Dig
아님 큐라레에 중독된
디글을 데려온 건요?
down here when he was
poisoned with curare.
난 둘 모두에게
할 일 했던거야!
The difference is that
I did my homework on both of you!
난 사람들에게 그냥
쉽게 털어놓지 않아
I don't just
tell people easily.
전 말하지
않을 거에요
I'm not going
to tell anyone.
제겐 감사할 필요 없지만
그녀에겐 고맙다고 하세요
And you don't have to thank me,
but you should thank her
바보 만들지 마시고
instead of being
kind of a jerk.
미스터 퀸
Mr. Queen.
집에 잠시 들르렴
집에 가야겠어
I have to go home.
벙커에서 나와
싸웠던 남자는
That man that I fought
in the bunker,
대량 생산하는데 필요한
모든 걸 이미 갖고 있어
he has what he needs
to mass produce
섬의 혈청 말야
the serum from the island.
그를 멈춰야 해
And we have to stop him.
그가 목을 움켜쥐었을 때
회장님 피부를 만졌으니
He touched your skin
when he grabbed your neck.
피부에서 잔유(殘油)를
추출할 수 있었죠
I was able to absorb
the residual oils from his skin,
젤 기반의 중합체와
더해진다면
which, when added
to a gel-based polymer,
그의 지문을 되살려
낼 수 있을 거에요
might be able
to recreate his fingerprint.
당신이 생각했던
영웅은 아니겠죠?
Never meet
your heroes, right?
엄마?
Mom?
올리버, 집에
들러줘서 고맙구나
Oliver, thank you
for coming home, sweetheart.
괜찮으세요?
Is everything all right?
글쎄, 모르겠다
Well, I don't know.
네 동생은 방문을
걸어 잠그고
Your sister has locked
herself in her room
나와 이야기도
하지 않으니
and she won't
talk to me.
- 걱정마세요. 제가 말해보죠
- 그래
- Don't worry, I'll talk to her.
- Ok.
크리스마스네요
It's Christmas.
그래
Yes.
하지만 얼마 전
행사 생각해보면
But given the last
gala that we threw,
올해 크리스마스 파티는
건너뛰는게 좋겠구나
I think we're going to skip
this year's Christmas party.
테아, 오빠야
문 열어봐
Thea, it's Ollie.
Open the door.
아냐, 지금은, 오빠
Not--not now, Ollie.
어서, 문 열어!
Speedy,
open the door!
- 엄마와 같이 있어?
- 아니!
- Is mom with you?
- No!
무슨 일이야?
What's going on?
- 엄마에게 보여주기 싫어
- 뭘?
- I didn't want mom to see.
- See what?
이 친구
무슨 일이지?
What happened to him?
자경단원이 사격
연습에 이용했지
Vigilante decided to use him
as target practice.
네가 맞아
You're right--
그 자는 사이코야
the guy's a psycho.
왜 병원에는
안 간거지?
Why didn't you go
to the hospital?
이 도시에서 화살은
총알과 마찬가지죠
In this city, an arrow's
the same as a bullet
경찰을 끌어들인다면
if you want the cops involved.
엄마도 사실
로이를 좋아해
And mom actually
likes Roy,
트리 장식 초대도
취소하실거야
but something tells me she'd revoke
his tree trimming invitation
후드와 어울리는걸
엄마가 아신다면
if she found out he was
messing around with the Hood.
Uh-huh.
안녕
Hi.
로이
Roy.
꽤 아플거야
This is going
to hurt.
내 분노가 고통을
삭이는 중이니까
My anger's dulling the pain.
이거면 통증이
더 줄어들겠죠
This will
dull it better.
계속 압박 해
Going to put
pressure on it.
바로 거기
Right there.
디글, 집으로
와줬으면 해
Diggle, I need you to come
to the Queen mansion.
로이가 맞았어
Roy's been shot.
화살이야
With an arrow.
이야기가 길어
It's a long story.
테아 방에서 구급
상자도 좀 부탁해
Look, just bring the first aid kit
to Thea's room.
고마워
Thank you.
로이, 운전사
디글이라고
Roy, my driver, Mr. Diggle,
군대에서 복무할 때
의료 훈련을 받았지
he has medical training
from his time in the army.
- 그가 봉합해 줄거야
- 고마워요
- He's going to patch you up.
- Thank you.
최소한의 성의지
It's the least I can do.
이봐, 셋이 무슨
짓인지 모르지만
Look, I don't know what
the three of you are up to,
아마 자경단원은 자넬
구하려고 그랬을 거야
but maybe the vigilante
was just trying to keep you safe.
로이를 쏴서?
By shooting Roy?
그냥... 하는 말이야
I...I'm just saying.
그냥 잊는
편이 좋겠어
Maybe you should
let this go.
그래서...
So...
그냥 잊어버리자고?
Are you going
to let this go?
아니
No.
하지만 이젠
내 방식이야
But now we're going
to do things my way.
엄마!
Mom!
저기요!
Hello!
샤도?
Shado?
당신은 여기
있으면 안돼
You can't be here.
당신을 봐야 했어
I had to see you.
- 경고해야 했으니까
- 내게 경고를?
- Had to warn you.
- Warn me?
다가오는 것과
싸울 수 없어
You can't fight what's coming.
활을 내려 놔
Put down your bow.
내 아버지의
후드는 벗고
Take off my father's hood.
내가 후드를 입는 건
아버님을 기리는거야
I wear that hood
to honor your father.
너를 기리는 거고
And to honor you.
나를 기리고 싶다면
싸움을 멈추고... 살아남아
If you want to honor me,
stop fighting...and live.
아니면 모든 사람들이
당신이 죽길 바랄테니
Or everyone you love will die.
오빠?
Ollie?
누구와 이야기
하고 있었어?
Who were you
talking to?
저리 가!
Get over there!
미라크루야
Mirakuru.
데려가
Take them.
안토니...
Anthony...
원하는 걸
얻었잖아요
You got what
you wanted.
그들은 그냥
보내줘요
You can let them go.
내가 걱정된다면
If you ever
cared about me.
난 자네를 정말
걱정하지, 사라
But I do care about you, Sara.
그래서 죽이지
않았던 거고
Which is why
I won't choose to kill you.
하지만 그는 달라
But he might.
무슨 이야기를
하는 거죠?
What are you
talking about?
선택의 시간이네,
올리버
Time to choose, Oliver.
누가 살고,
누가 죽느냐
Who lives, and who dies.
빨리 결정해
30초가 지나면
But pick quickly,
because in 30 seconds,
둘 다 쏴버릴테니
I will shoot them both.
배양 과정이
막 시작됐습니다
The incubation
process has begun.
혈청 분배가 48시간
내에 준비될 겁니다
Serum will be ready
for distribution in 48 hours.
이틀이라
Two days.
자네를 백 명은 더
만들어 낼 수 있겠군
And we will be able to create
a hundred more like you.
게다가 이 시를
운영하는 자들은
And the people
who run this city
진정한 힘이 뭔지
지켜보게 될 테고
will see what
real power looks like.
자경단원에게도
동료가 있었네요
I knew the Vigilante
had partners.
이젠 애로우라고
불리길 좋아하지
He likes to be called
the Arrow now.
당신 셋은 정말 끔찍한
사람들과 말려들었군요
You three have messed
with some really nasty people.
돌 메이커,
카운트 버티고,
The Doll Maker,
Count Vertigo,
다저, 헌트리스,
Dodger, The Huntress.
기록까지 해두진
않았는데
We weren't
keeping score.
제가 해뒀죠
I was.
배리
Barry.
자네가 투여한 쥐약에
부작용이라도 있나?
The rat poison that you gave
me...are there any side effects?
네, 아마 환각이
있을 수 있어요
Um, yeah, I think
hallucinations, maybe.
그리고 다한증이요
And excessive sweating.
땀을 많이 흘리세요?
Are you sweating
excessively?
환각이 보여요?
You're
hallucinating?
뭐가 보이죠?
What are you
seeing?
샤도라는 여자가
섬에 같이 있었어
A girl named Shado
that was with me on the island.
샤도
Shado.
사라
Sara.
함께 고립됐던
여자가 몇이죠?
How many women were
you marooned with?
그 정도면 환상의
섬 아니었나여?
Are you sure
this wasn't fantasy island?
정글이나 숲에서
훈련하셨군요
You did train in a jungle
or forest environment,
그래서 녹색인 거죠
hence the green.
저기, 핼액 검사로
뭐가 나오는지 보죠
Hey, let me draw some
blood, see what's up.
좀 물어봐도 되요?
Hey, can I ask you
something?
왜 마스크는 없죠?
Why no mask?
하는 일까지 묻지는
않을께요... 다만,
Not to tell you how to
do your vigilante...ing,
분장용 화장품은요?
but the grease paint
thing?
신원 숨기시는게
좀 어설프잖아요
It's a poor
identity concealer.
그럼 찾아주지 그래
내 얼굴에 맞으면서
So find me a mask that conforms
perfectly to my face
달릴 때도 내 능력에
영향이 없는 것으로
and doesn't affect my ability
to aim while I'm on the run.
압축성 극세사를
찾아 보세요
You should look into
a compressible micro fabric.
- 멋지겠는데요
- 사이러스 골드를 찾았어요
- It could be great.
- I found Cyrus Gold.
사이러스 골드가
누구지?
Who's Cyrus Gold?
얼마전 자네를 죽음까지
몰고 갔던 인간 병기지
The human weapon that left you
nearly dead the other night.
저 친구가 자네 목에서
지문을 떠냈잖나
The kid did manage
to pull his print off your neck.
제가 안면 인식
프로그램을 돌려서
I've had facial
recognition software
도시 전체 폐쇄 회로
카메라를 스캔했죠
scanning closed circuit
cameras all over town.
지금 델가도와 25번가
모퉁이에 있어요
He's at the corner
of Delgado and 25th right now,
하지만 이제 그를
막 놓칠 참이네요
but we're just about
to lose him.
그 교차로에
또 뭐가 있지?
What else is at
that intersection?
주차장, 시장,
모텔이 있네요
A parking lot,
a market, a motel.
그의 은신처겠군
Could be where he's holed up.
- 내가 맡지
- 올리버...
- I got this.
- Oliver...
이번엔 내가
처리하면 어떨까?
Why don't let me
handle this one?
단지 정찰이잖나
It's just recon.
좋아
Fine.
하지만 지원차
나도 가지
But I'm going
as your back-up.
걱정 말아요
Don't worry.
뭐가 문제인지
밝혀낼 테니까
I'll figure out what's
wrong with Oliver.
먼저 알아내야 해요
You'd be the first.
숨은 숭배자?
Secret admirer?
아니, 사실은
아빠에게 온 거야
No, actually,
they're from my father.
어떻게들 왔지?
What brings you by?
언니 도움이 필요해요
신디 친구가 살해됐는데
We need your help.
Cindy's friend was murdered,
경찰은 조사를
하려들지 않아요
but the police aren't
going to investigate.
마약 과도 복용으로
그냥 끝내려고 해요
They said that he ODed,
end of story.
이걸 보세요
Check this out.
그는 헌혈을 해서
가욋 돈을 벌었죠
He earned extra money
donating blood.
맥스의 아파트에서 찾았어요
마약 중독자였다면
We found it in Max's apartment.
They wouldn't have accepted
피를 받지도 않았겠죠
his blood if he was
using, right?
그는 헌혈 캠페인과
같은 날 실종됐어요
Max went missing
the same day as the Blood Drive.
그가 거기서
헌혈 했다면
If he did
donate blood there,
적어도 그들은 무슨 일이
있었는지 알고 있을테죠
maybe they at least know
something that happened to him.
내가 알아볼께
I'll ask around.
고마워요, 로럴
Thank you, Laurel.
지루하면 글러브 박스에
퍼즐 책을 넣어놨으니까
If you get bored, I keep a book
of crossword puzzles in the glove box.
재미 없다고
That's not funny.
좋아, 뭐가 보이지?
Ok, what do you see?
깨끗해
It's clean.
너무 깨끗해
Really clean.
솔로몬 그런디는
월요일에 태어나
"Solomon Grundy,
born on a Monday."
화요일에 세례받고
Christened on Tuesday.
나도 그 시 알아
삶의 7단계를 상징하지
I know the poem.
It symbolizes the seven stages of life--
탄생에서 죽음까지
from birth to death.
이 친구는 어느 단계지?
What stage is this guy in?
가, 가, 가, 가, 가!
Go, go, go, go, go!
아무렇지도 않게
날 들어올리더군
He picked me up
like I was nothing.
- 펠리시티, 지원 요청해
- 알았어요
- Felicity, call for back-up.
- On it.
사라에 대한 건가?
This about Sara?
소식이라도 있어?
You heard from her?
아뇨
No.
죄송해요. 이건...
I'm sorry,
this is...
다른 문제에요
This is
something else.
사이러스 골드
Cyrus Gold.
지난 주,
퀸 기업의
He robbed
the Applied Sciences Division
응용과학부서를
털었던 자죠
of Queen Consolidated
last week.
형사님...
Detective...
그는 극도로
위험한 자에요
He's extremely
dangerous.
센트럴 시티에서
왔다는 CSI 친구,
The CSI kid from Central City,
그 친구 말로는
괴물같았다면서
he said this guy was like
some kind of monster.
그래요
He is.
뭐지, 스테로이드?
Well, what is it, steroids?
더 안좋아요, 그건...
Worse. It's--
그러니까...
it's...
자네를 믿는다고 쳐도
왜 내게 온거지?
Well, assuming I believe
you, why come to me?
제가 타협했으니까요
I've been
compromised.
무슨 뜻이지?
What does that mean?
제 책임이란 뜻이죠
It means I'd be
a liability.
제 말 명심하세요, 형사님
You have to take my word
on this, Detective.
가능한 대로 많은
사람들을 모으세요
Gather as many men
as you can,
사이러스 골드를 죽일
것을 주저하지 마세요
and do not hesitate
to kill Cyrus Gold.
기회가 주어진다면
Because if given
the opportunity,
형사님에게도
똑같이 할 테니까요
he'll do the same
to you.
이럴 필요 없어!
You don't have
to do this!
여기 온 목적은
달성했잖아!
You got what
you came for!
그냥 받고 꺼져!
Just take it and go!
10초...
10 seconds.
이 미치광이
사이코패스!
You freaking
psychopath!
역사가 판단하겠지
History will make that judgment.
5초...
Five seconds.
시간 됐군
Time's up.
아니, 아냐!
No, no!
결정을 내린거군
I guess you made
your choice.
안돼!
No!
- 왔군
- 그래
Hi.
어떻게 왔지?
What are you
doing here?
테아를 보러왔어
I came by to see Thea.
아, 들어와
Oh. Go on in.
윗층 자기 방에 있어
She's upstairs
in her room.
집으로 오는
길에 보니까
I noticed on the drive up
that your house
크리스마스 장식이
없던데
wasn't festooned
with Christmas decorations.
그러게, 올해는
Well, we didn't feel
very much like
그럴 기분이 아니라
festooning
this year.
무슨 말인지 알겠어
I know what you mean.
작년 크리스마스에는
I remember last Christmas,
토마와 내가 여기
파티에 왔었는데
Tommy and I came here
for your party.
내게 오랫 동안
최고의 휴일이었지
It was one of the best holidays
I'd had in a really long time.
어쨌든, 가서 테아와
이야기 해볼께
Anyway, I should probably
go talk to Thea.
헌혈 캠페인을
확인해 봤는데
I checked into
the Blood Drive,
모두 합법적이야
and it's all legitimate.
세바스티안의
행동은 사실,
In fact, what
Sebastian's done
생명을 구하는데
많은 도움이 됐거든
has helped save
a lot of lives.
그 캠페인이 계속
승승장구한다면
So if the Blood Drive
is on the up and up,
맥스의 살인범은
어떻게 찾을거죠?
then how are we supposed
to find Max's killer?
다른 방법이 있지
There's one
other thing.
캠페인의 모든
혈액 기증자는
All of the blood
donors at the drive
랭포드 협회로부터
were subjected
to a psych evaluation
정신 감정을
받았거든
by the Langford
Institute.
그거... 합법적이에요?
Is that, like, legal?
딱히 특별한 건 없어
It's not entirely
out of the norm.
맥스가 중독됐는지
협회 사람들은
And while someone
at the institute might know
알지도 모르지만
if Max was on drugs,
영장 없이는 알아낼
방법이 없어
there's no way of finding out
without a warrant.
결국 우리가 알아낼
방법은 없는거지
Which we're certainly
not going to get.
미안해
도움이 안되서
I'm sorry
I couldn't be more help.
뭐하는거죠?
What are you doing?
장난 좀 치고 있죠
Uh, just messing around
with something.
올리버의 환각을
일으켰던게 뭔지
Shouldn't you be
trying to figure out
알아내야 하는거
아니에요?
what's causing Oliver's
hallucinations?
샘플은 아직 스캔중이죠
오래 걸리면 안되는데
Sample's still being scanned.
Shouldn't be too much longer.
정말 걱정되는군요,
안 그래요?
You're really worried
about him, huh?
지나친 위험을
감수하고 있죠
He takes crazy chances.
비록 그게
섬의 미녀에 대한
Even when he's not
hallucinating
환각이 아닐 때도요
about beautiful
island girls.
음
Hmm.
요전 날 밤, 올리버를
좋아하는지 물어봤잖아요
The other night,
I asked you if you liked Oliver.
말했죠. 아니라고
I told you.
I don't.
기억하죠
I remember.
그랬다고 해도...
But if you did...
왜인지 알 것 같아요
I could see why.
그러니까, 올리버 퀸은
I mean, Oliver Queen.
낮에는 백만장자에,
He is a billionaire by day
밤에는 도시까지 구하죠
and saves the city by night.
데이트하고
싶은거군요
Sounds like
you want to date him.
바라봐주지 않는
사람과 연결되는
I just have a little experience
with liking someone
경험은 조금 있죠
who doesn't see you
the same way.
오늘 밤, 논란의 대상인
STAR 연구실의
Protests continue
into the final countdown
분자 가속기
가동식에 대한
for tonight's ignition of
S.T.A.R. Lab's
항의는 절정으로
치닫고 있습니다
controversial
particle accelerator.
STAR 연구실의 창업자인 해리슨
웰스는 과학적 진보의 새 시대가
S.T.A.R. Lab's founder Harrison Wells
promises a new era
가까이 도래했다고
장담하고 있습니다
of scientific
advancement is at hand.
아무래도 가동식까지는
돌아오지 못하겠네요
I guess I won't be back in time
to see them turn it on.
알아, 미친 소리지
I know, it sounds crazy.
인간 병기?
Human weapons?
이봐, 그의 이름은
사이러스 골드야
Look, his name is Cyrus Gold.
지난 주 퀸 그룹에
침입했지
He's the one that broke into
Queen Consolidated last week.
은행 계좌 역시
그가 털어갔고
He's the one that
robbed the blood bank.
그가 전부 죽인거야
And he killed all those people.
Wait, hold on a second.
이봐, 이 정보는
어디서 얻은건가
Where are you
getting all this intel?
아, 친구. 그게
무슨 상관이람
Oh, man, what's
a matter with you?
자경단원과 이야기하는 것
만으로도 자넨 강등감이야
Talking to the Vigilante's what
got you demoted in the first place.
이봐, 소규모로 가지
Look, we take a small squad.
SWAT 팀의 매카시와
에반스면 되, 존스
McCarthy and Evans
from SWAT, Jones.
우린 이 자를
잡아넣을거야
We can bring this guy down.
지니와 약속했다고
크리스마스 쇼핑에 데려간다고
I promised Jeannie
I'd take her Christmas shopping.
루카스
Lucas.
제발
Please.
좋아
Fine.
하지만 지니한테는
자네가 전화하게
But you get to call
Jeanie and tell her
같이 못간다고
I'm not taking her
shopping.
반장님, 선을 넘을
생각은 없습니다만
Hey, sir. I don't
mean to overstep,
추가 인원
필요하십니까?
but could you guys
use an extra man?
조끼 챙기게,
데일리 경관
Grab a vest, Officer Daily.
경찰에 골드에게
접근중입니다
The police are onto Gold.
그를 찾고 있어요
They're looking for him.
제가 팀 내에
들어왔습니다
I made sure
I'm in the loop.
경찰이 방해하도록 놔두기엔
우린 이제 끝이 보인다고
We are too close
to let the police interfere.
사이러스 동지
Brother Cyrus.
경찰이 자네를
애타게 찾고 있네
The police
are eager to meet you.
스스로 소개하게나
Introduce yourself.
크리스마스에
계획이라도 있어요?
So, any plans for Christmas?
메노라를 밝혀야죠
(유대교 하누카 의식에
쓰이는 전통 촛대)
Lighting my menorah.
이봐
Hey.
기분은 어때요?
Hi. How are you feeling?
좋아. 다만...
Fine. Just...
집이 좀 붐비길래
It's a little bit
crowded at my house,
혼자 있을까 해서
이리 와본거지
and I wanted to come
down here to get a little privacy.
네
Yeah.
가요, 배리
Come on, Barry.
빅 벨리 버거에서
카운트다운을 지켜봐야죠
We can watch the countdown
at Big Belly Burger.
혈액 분석은
거의 끝났어요
Your blood analysis
is almost done.
고맙군
Thank you.
문제가 뭐지, 친구?
What's the matter, kid?
마치 귀신이라도
본 표정인데
You look like
you've seen a ghost.
그가 안에 있는게
확실하나?
Are you sure he's in?
네, 섹터 차량이 사이러스의
출입을 감지했습니다
Yes, sir. Sector car
spotted Cyrus Gold entering.
아직 떠나지 않았구요
He hasn't left.
안전장치 해제하게
Safeties off.
멋진 곳이군
This is a nice place.
좀더 안락하군
It's a bit more
comfortable
그 섬의
비행기 기체보다
than the fuselage
on the island.
자넨 진짜가 아니야
You're not real.
자네도 아니지
Neither are you.
자넨 모두에게 말했지
이 계획을 시작하면서
You told everyone
when you started this crusade
자네 아버지의 죄를
보상하는 거라고
that it was about
making up
for your father's sins.
거짓말이지
That was a lie.
이건 자네 죄의
속죄일 뿐이야
This charade is to atone
for your sins.
자넨 죽었어
You're dead.
영웅이 아니고
You are not a hero.
친구도 아니지
Or a friend.
형제도 아냐
아무 것도 아니라고
Or a brother.
You are nothing.
내게서 등을
돌리지 말게
Do not turn your back on me,
다시는
not again.
자넨 죽었어
You're gone.
내가 어디에 있든...
Wherever I am...
이제는 우리가
함께 할 때야
It's time you joined me.
겁장이는 천 번을
죽는다고들 하지
They say a coward
dies a thousand deaths.
자넨 그걸로도 모자라
But even that wouldn't
be enough for you.
난 자넬 구하려 했어!
I tried to save you!
그녀도
And her.
하지만 그러지 못했지
But you couldn't.
네가 이 도시를
구하지 못한 것처럼
Just like you couldn't
save this city.
그 섬은 자네를 강하게
만든게 아니야, 애송이
The island didn't
make you strong, kid.
자네의 유약함을
드러냈을 뿐이지
It revealed you to be weak.
쇼핑 도와줘서
고마워요
Thank you for being
my shopping guide.
괜찮아요?
Are you ok?
어, 네, 그러니까...
Uh, yeah, it's just, um,
뭐 물어봐도 될까요?
can I ask you a question?
후원하신 헌혈
캠페인 말이에요
It's about the Blood Drive
you sponsored.
물론이죠
의도가 좋잖아요
Of course.
It's a wonderful cause.
특히 경영난에 시달리는
병원들을 상대하고 있죠
Especially with the underfunded
hospitals we're dealing with.
그게 어때서요?
What about it?
여보세요?
Hello?
뭐라구요?!
What?!
아, 제가 곧 가죠
Ok, I'll be right over.
무슨 일이죠?
What happened?
제 아빠요. 음...
My father. Um...
중환자실에 계신데요
죄송해요
He's in the ICU.
I'm so sorry.
너무 죄송해요
가봐야겠어요
I'm so sorry, I have to go.
죄송해요
I'm sorry.
여기 무슨 일이죠?
What happened
in here?
- 누군가 침입했나요?
- 아니
- Did someone break in?
- No.
혈액 분석이 끝났네요
좋은 소식이에요
Your blood analysis
is done. Good news.
뭔지 밝혀졌나?
So you know
what's in my system?
그게 문제에요
회장님 피는 깨끗해요
That's the thing--
your blood's clean.
아무 문제가 없다구요
There's nothing
wrong with you.
그럼 왜 환각이
보이는거지?!
Then why am I hallucinating?!
모르죠
I don't know.
하지만 그
문제가 뭐든
But whatever
your problem is,
약물 쪽은 아니에요
심리적인거죠
it's not pharmacological.
It's psychological.
- 그 머리 속에요
- 내 머리라...
- It's in your head.
- It's in my head.
이런, 맙소사
Oh, my God.
올리버
Oliver.
아빠!
Dad!
그래
Honey.
얘야
발가락이 움직여지니
좋은 신호 아니겠니
Well, I can wiggle my toes,
it must be a good sign.
난 괜찮아
괜찮다고
I'm all right,
honey, I'm fine.
루카스는 어때, 괜찮니?
How's Lucas, is he all right?
그게... 죄송...
I--I'm sorry.
무슨 말이니?
What do you mean?
지니에게는 내가 전화하마
와이프에게도 전화해야지
I got to call Jeannie.
I got to call his wife.
아뇨, 아빠, 제가 할께요
아빠는... 여기 계세요
No, Dad, I'll do it.
You just...stay here.
쉬어두시라구요
Get some rest.
여기 어쩐 일이죠?
What are you
doing here?
아버님이 괜찮은지
확인해 두려구요
Wanted to make sure
your father was ok.
괜찮으세요
He is.
당신도 괜찮은지
확인할 겸
I wanted to make sure
you were, too.
어떻습니까, 형사님?
How are you, Detective?
살아있잖나
I'm alive.
다른 대원들 볼
면목이 없군
Unlike most everyone else
in my unit.
파트너 일은
유감입니다
I'm sorry
about your partner.
그를 잡을 뻔 했어
I took him in there.
저 때문이군요
Because of me.
실망시켜서
미안하지만
I hate to disappoint you,
이 도시의 모든 죽음이
다 자네 책임은 아닐세
but not every death
in this city is on you.
이걸 그에게서
떼어냈지
I got this off Gold.
그걸로 뭔가
할 수 있겠지
Hopefully you can
do something with it.
처음엔 믿지 않았네
하지만, 이 친구...
I didn't believe it
at first, but this guy,
인간이 아닌 것 같아
I mean, it's like
he's not human.
그는 인간이에요
He's human.
그럼 자네가
죽일 수 있겠군
Well, then you can kill him.
힐튼과 나를
위해서
For Hilton. And me.
내가 보기엔 충분히
날카로운 것 같은데
I think those
are sharp enough.
내겐 안 그래
Apparently I'm not.
디글, 내가 정신을
놓은 것 같나?
Diggle, do you think
I'm losing my mind?
나머지만 하겠어
No more than
the rest of us.
난 봤어...
I saw...
슬레이드 윌슨을
Slade Wilson.
그는 섬에서의
친구였지
Slade was my friend
on the island,
게다가...
and...
샤도처럼
나 때문에 죽었지
like Shado,
he is dead because of me.
렌스씨가 그러더군
Mr. Lance
just told me
도시의 모든 죽음이
내 책임은 아니라고
that not every
death in this city is my fault.
좋아
Fine.
그래도 너무 많아
There are plenty
that are.
아프가니스탄에서
돌아왔을 때...
When I got home
from Afghanistan, I...
귀신을 봤지. 나도...
saw a ghost, too.
살아남은 자의
죄책감이랄까
Survivor's guilt.
왜 우리일까
그들이 아니라
Why us, not them.
왜 그런지 알지
I know why.
그럼 '왜 우리지'는
우리 문제가 아니야
Then the "why's"
not your problem.
그럼 자네는 귀신은
어떻게 쫓아버렸지?
How'd you make
your ghost go away?
내게 무슨 말을
하려는지 알아봤지
I figured out what they were
trying to tell me.
뭐였는데?
Which was?
들어달라는거야, 올리버
That's for me to hear, Oliver.
무슨 말을 하려는지
자네도 알아봐야지
You have to figure out what
yours is trying to tell you.
여기 뭔가
나왔어요
Guys, we got
something here.
랜스가 준 열쇠를
스캔해 봤어요
I scanned the key
Lance gave you,
일련번호를 역추적해
제조자를 밝혀냈는데
and traced its serial code
back to the manufacturer.
이 특별한
열쇠가 맞는 건
This particular key
fits a locked gate
글레이드의 크레센트
서클의 어딘가에요
somewhere on Crescent Circle
in the Glades.
어디 가는거죠?
Where are you going?
지금 그 상태로
나가면 안 돼요
You can't go out there
in your condition.
내가 멈춰야 해
I have to stop this.
골드는 올리버를
초죽음까지 만들었어요
Oliver, Gold
left you half dead,
힐튼 형사에게 한 짓보다
50%는 더 양호한 거에요
which is 50 percent better than
how he left Detective Hilton.
펠리시티...
Felicity...
내겐 선택권이 없어
I don't have
a choice.
돌아올 거야
I'll come back.
약속해요?
Promise me.
준비 됐습니다
It's ready.
여기서 맥스
스탠튼을 죽였나?
Is this where you killed
Max Stanton, hmm?
뭐하는거지?
What are you doing?
내게 그걸 주사하면
당신 죽여버릴거야
If you stick that
in me, I'll kill you.
아니, 로이 동지
No, brother Roy.
날 위해
죽이게 될 걸
You'll kill for me.
사이러스 동지 말로는
자넬 죽였다고 하던데
Brother Cyrus
told me he killed you.
생각만큼 강한
친구가 아니었겠지
Guess he's not as strong
as you'd hoped.
미라크루는 어디서 났지?
화학식은 누가 준 건가?
Where'd you get the Mirakiru?
Who gave you the formula?!
도시를 구하기위해
사용할 선물이랄까
It was a gift. A gift I would use
to save this city from itself.
또 실패군
Another failure.
일어나, 올리버
Get up, Oliver.
토미?
Tommy?
자네는 여기서
죽어선 곤란해
You're not going
to die down here.
토미, 미안해
Tommy, I'm sorry.
널 죽게 방치했어
I let you die.
넌 방치한게
아냐, 올리버
You didn't
let me die, Ollie.
날 구하려고
싸웠지
You fought
to save me.
그게 자네
일이었으니까
Because that's
what you do.
늘 해왔던
일이기도 했고
What you have
always done.
생존을 위해
싸워야지
You fight to survive.
자네를 살인자라
부른것도 기억해
I know I called you
a murderer,
하지만 자넨 아냐
but you are not.
자넨 영웅이야
You are a hero.
자넨 섬과 싸웠지
You beat the island.
내 아버지와 싸웠고
You beat my father.
그러니 싸워, 올리버
So fight, Oliver.
일어나서
Get up
다시 싸워
and fight back.
죽여버려
Kill him.
이봐. 난 누구도 죽게
내버려두지 않을거야!
Hey. I am not leaving
anyone else to die!
자네 강해, 친구
You're strong, kid.
어서! 어서!
Come on! Come on!
C어서, 로이!
Come on, Roy!
싸워. 어서
싸우라고!
Fight. Come on, fight!
로이?!
Roy?!
이봐, 로이!
Hey, Roy!
어디 있었어?
온통 찾아다녔잖아!
Where have you been?
I've been looking all over for you!
난...
I was...
다른 단서를
쫓고 있었어
I was running down
another lead.
잘 되진 않았지만
It didn't pan out.
난 또 자경단원을
뒤쫓는 줄 알았지
I thought you were
chasing after the Vigilante again.
너무 무서웠어. 무슨
일이라도 있을까 봐
I got so scared. I thought
something happened to you.
이봐, 걱정하지 마
Hey, hey, don't worry.
난 살아있잖아
I'm alive.
전 스탈링 시민들을
지켜주고 싶습니다
I want to serve
the people of Starling,
시를 가졌다고 생각하는
자들이 아니라 말입니다
not the men and women
who think they own it.
우린 도시를 재건하는데
도움을 줄 수 있습니다
Together, we can help
rebuild our city
엘리트도 없고 억압받는
사람들도 없는 도시로
into a place where there are
no elites and no oppressed.
모두가 형제고
자매인 도시로
Where we are all
brothers and sisters.
자네 선거가
시작됐군
So your campaign begins.
도시는 리더가
필요하니까요
The city
needs a leader.
그리고 모방범
후드를 부추겨
And putting
the copycat hoods
시장을 암살하도록
만드는게 첫 단계죠
up to assassinating
the mayor was just the first step.
그 자경단원이...
The Vigilante...
원심분리기와
He destroyed
the centrifuge
혈청까지
파괴했습니다
and the serum
along with it.
내 피에서 다시 샘플을
얻어내도록 준비해두지
I will arrange for you to receive
another sample of my blood,
그럼 자네는 다시 혈청을
대량생산 할 수 있을테니
and then you can begin
to mass produce the serum again.
자네에게 자경단원과
맞서지 말라고 했지
When I ask you not
to confront the Vigilante,
내 말 듣게
you will listen.
기억해, 자네 마스크는
대체될 수도 있으니까
Remember, your mask
can be worn by another.
후드를 쓴 남자를
아시겠군요, 그렇죠?
You know who he is
under that hood, don't you?
정확히 알고 있지
I know exactly who he is.
그는 내 친구니까
He's my friend.
그래서 그가 죽지
않았으면 하는군요
That's why you don't
want him dead.
죽음은 그의 삶에서
해방이 될 테고,
Death would be
a release from this life,
그의 맹세도 아직
실행되지 못했거든
and his sentence is yet
to be carried out.
아끼는 모든 사람들을
그에게서 떼어 놓겠네
I am going to tear everything
he cares about away from him.
그의 추종자들은
파멸시킬 테고
Destroy those who choose
to follow him.
그가 사랑한 사람은
타락하게 만들거야
Corrupt those he loves.
그가 모든 사람들과
Once he has lost everyone
아끼는 모든 걸
잃고난 후에...
and everything he values...
그의 눈동자에
화살을 박아주지
I will drive an arrow
through his eye.
샤도...
Shado...
샤도!
Shado!
아!
Ahhh!
안 돼!
No!
왜?
Why?
난...
I...
그녀를 쏜 건
아이보에요
Ivo just shot her.
왜 그랬는지는
말하지 않았어요
He didn't say why.
누가 그랬 건...
Whoever did this to her...
고통받게 되겠지
is going to suffer.
아직도 환각
문제가 있나?
Still have a ghost problem?
아니
No.
메세지는 받았네
I got the message.
하지만 우린...
But we...
다른 문제가 있어
We have other problems.
안 그랬으면
우리도 아니지
Wouldn't be us
if we didn't.
로이에게
혈청이 투여됐어
Roy was injected
with the serum.
맙소사, 괜찮대요?
Oh, my God, is he ok?
살아는 있어
He's alive.
하지만 계속
지켜봐야지
But we are going
to have to keep an eye on him.
사이러스 골드는?
And Cyrus Gold?
토요일에 죽었어
일요일에 묻혔고
Died on Saturday,
buried on Sunday.
하지만 함께
일하던 자가 있더군
But he was working
with someone.
내가 봤지
마스크를 썼던데
I saw him,
he wore a mask
그림이 있던데
아, 해골이었어
with the image
of a...of a skull.
군대를 만들기 위해
혈청을 대량생산 중이야
He's trying to mass produce
the serum to build an army.
무엇 때문에?
For what?
자네도 군인이잖아
You're a soldier.
군대의 주
목적이 뭘까?
What's the primary
purpose of an army?
전쟁이군
War.
배리는 어디 있지?
Where's Barry?
센트럴 시티로 돌아갔어요
He went back to Central City.
Oh.
분자 가속기 가동식에 맞춰
돌아가고 싶다고 했거든요
Wanted to get home in time to see
them turn on the particle accelerator.
이건 받을께요
I should take this.
여보세요
Hi.
Hey
도착했어요?
Did you make it?
늦지 않게 센트럴 시티로
돌아오긴 했는데
I made it back
to Central City in time,
하지만 STAR 연구실에
입장하는 건 실패했죠
but I missed the cut off
in line at S.T.A.R. Labs.
늦었거든요, 평소처럼
I was late, as usual.
하지만 다시는
안 늦을 거에요
But in spirit
of not being late again,
올리버 퀸이...
uh, if you ever decide that
당신 취향이 아니라니
Oliver Queen
isn't the guy for you;
만약 다른 사람과
if you decide that
데이트 나갈...
you want to go
on a date with
생각이 있으면, 음...
someone else, um...
알아줘요. 그 친구 이번엔
제 시간에 나타날 테니까
You should know that
that guy, he'll be on time.
알게되서 좋군요
Good to know.
저기, 올리버에게
뭔가 남겨놨는데
Oh, hey, and I left
something for Oliver.
좋아했으면
좋겠어요
I hope he likes it.
안녕, 배리
Bye, Barry.
그래요, 펠리시티
Bye, Felicity.
린다 카프입니다. STAR 연구소
밖에서 현재 생방송 중입니다
I'm Linda Park and we're live
outside S.T.A.R. Labs
현재의 악천후 상태는 더욱
악화될 것으로 예상됩니다
despite the inclement weather,
which is only going to get worse.
폭우로 모든 시위자들은
거의 물러난 상황이지만
The torrential downpour has
driven away almost all the protesters
STAR 연구소 CEO인 해리슨 윌스는
오늘 밤 폭풍은 분가 가속기에
though S.T.A.R. Labs
CEO Harrison Wells has assured us
어떤 영향도 미치지 않을
것이며, 모든게 순조롭게
that the storm tonight will in
no way affect the particle accelerator,
진행될 것이라...
which is up
and running smoothly.
방금 연구소에서 대피
명령이 떨어졌답니다
Wait, we are now
being told to evacuate the facility.
폭풍은 주 냉각
시스템의 오작동에
The storm may have
caused a malfunction
영향을 미친게 아닌가
판단하고 있습니다
to the primary
cooling system.
관련자들은 분자 가속기의
폐쇄를 시도하고 있지만
Officials are now trying to shut down
the particle accelerator,
시스템 통제의 회복에
어려움을 겪고 있습니다
but so far have been unable
to regain control of the system.
애로우도 크리스마스
선물을 받을 만 하지
Even the Arrow deserves
a Christmas present.
줘봐요
Here.
좀 어때?
How do I look?
영웅 같은데요
Like a hero.
Sync, corrected by elderman
www.addic7ed.com
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
한글자막 by 클라투
www.jinubeck.com